[A little child calls loudly: “Mataji! Jai!”.]
(malé dítì nahlas volá: „Mátadí! Dej!“)
Today's puja we have arranged of Durga or the Kali.
Dnes jsme uspoøádali púdu pro Durgu nebo Kálí.
That is the destroying form of the Goddess of all the evil and negativity.
Je to destruktivní forma Bohynì nièící všechno zlo a negativitu.
This we had to do it in France,
Dìláme ji ve Francii,
because I feel very strongly that day by day, in general,
protoe velmi silnì cítím, e všeobecnì ze dne na den
France is going down and down and down.
Francie stále klesá a klesá.
While you people are coming up,
Zatímco vy lidé rostete,
the rest of the France is in the most pitiable condition.
zbytek Francie zùstává v alostném stavu.
Firstly, as you understand, is the Catholic church,
Nejprve, jak chápete, je tu katolická církev.
which - perhaps you are not aware of, perhaps maybe -
Nejste si toho tøeba vìdomi - moná -
because you don't read any other languages,
protoe neètete v ádnıch jinıch jazycích,
you just read French compulsorily by this country.
prostì v této zemi musíte èíst francouzsky.
So you have no international views or international news
Take nemáte ádné mezinárodní pohledy ani mezinárodní znalosti,
that this Catholic church has done so many horrible things in the past,
e tato katolická církev v minulosti udìlala tolik strašnıch vìcí,
that is unbelievable that they have anything to do with God.
e je nepravdìpodobné, aby to mìlo nìco spoleèného s Bohem.
They burnt many cardinals in the hearth - roasted them.
Upálili na hranici mnoho kardinálù
Not only that, they killed so many people
Nejen to, zabili tolik lidí,
who ever tried to utter a word about them.
kteøí se o nich jen pokusili promluvit.
They were much worse than Muslim people.
Byli mnohem horší ne muslimové.
They went to other countries like South America, America -
Šli do jinıch zemí, jako je Jiní Amerika, Amerika
all these places they're all Catholics - even our country.
- všechna tato místa jsou katolická - dokonce i do naší zemì.
And they killed millions and millions of people.
A zabili miliony a miliony lidí.
Now as this is Kruta Yuga that has started,
Teï, kdy Krita juga zaèala,
one of the things as I said yesterday is that:
jednou z vìcí je - jak jsem øekla vèera,
you will have to pay for whatever you have done,
e budete muset platit za vše, co jste udìlali
on mass scale or individual scale.
- hromadnì èi jednotlivì.
If that is the case,
Pokud je to tento pøípad,
then one must know that France has to pay a lot
pak musíte vìdìt, e Francie musí platit draze
and this Catholic church has to pay more.
a e tato katolická církev musí platit ještì víc.
Catholic church has just taken out yarns out of their heads
Katolická církev jednoduše vybájila
and started a theory of original sin.
teorii prvotního høíchu.
That's how to condemn every other Incarnation, every other Prophet -
Odsoudit kadou další Inkarnaci, kadého dalšího proroka
that they were all with original sin.
- e všichni byli s prvotním høíchem.
And even they said Mary was born with original sin,
A dokonce øekli, e Marie se narodila s prvotním høíchem.
for many popes they were discussing it.
O tom hovoøilo mnoho papeù.
This shows that this whole hocus-pocus religion of Catholic church
Ukazuje se, e celé toto klamné náboenství katolické církve
had to establish itself by forcing people, by torturing them,
se upevnilo tím, e lidi nutilo, muèilo,
by taking all their ideas into their own control,
pøevzalo jejich myšlení pod vlastní kontrolu
give them funny ideas like original sin.
a vnuklo jim podivné nápady, jako je prvotní høích.
Another is that you must confess, giving them the left Vishuddhis.
Další vìcí je to, e musíte jít ke zpovìdi a dostanete levou Višudhi.
They treated women as nothing
Pøehlíeli eny, jako by byly vzduch
and to Mother of Mary they called Her a woman.
a Matku Marii nazıvali enou.
And this Paul, as I told you yesterday, is a fact.
A co se tıèe Pavla - jak jsem vám øíkala vèera - to je skuteènost.
Now it's necessary for Sahaja Yogis to understand
Sahadajogíni musí bezpodmíneènì pochopit,
how this Catholic church is so dangerous and has been doing such harm.
do jaké míry je katolická církev nebezpeèná a jaké zlo udìlala.
As there has been so many books about it -
Na toto téma však bylo tolik knih
that you people don't read, because it's not in French.
- které lidé neètou, protoe nejsou ve francouzštinì.
There are English books from America - you must learn English.
Jsou to anglické knihy z Ameriky - musíte se nauèit anglicky.
It's very important now I feel, that all the French must know English,
Je to velmi dùleité. Mám pocit, e všichni Francouzi
French will not give you the international personality
Francouzština vám neposkytne mezinárodní osobnost,
that you are supposed to acquire.
které máte dosáhnout.
You had some scholarship, not much.
Nìjaké znalosti máte - ne moc.
The real scholarship comes from England
Skuteèné znalosti pocházejí z Anglie
and also from America in English language, and also from India.
a také v angliètinì z Ameriky a také z Indie.
One gentleman who tried to translate all these things in UNESCO,
Pán, kterı se to všechno pokusil pøeloit na UNESCO,
he was thrown out by your media.
byl vašimi médii odmítnut.
Your media is taking full advantage that you don't read any other newspapers;
Vaše média vyuívají toho, e neètete ádné cizí noviny.
they are doing whatever they feel like.
Dìlají si, co se jim zlíbí.
All kinds of scandals, all kinds of sensationalization -
Všechny moné skandály a senzace
whatever they want to write, they write in free press.
- cokoli chtìjí psát, píší ve svobodném tisku.
On one side there's suppression of natural life of human beings,
Na jedné stranì dochází k potlaèení pøirozeného ivota lidskıch bytostí
let them to go to Freud.
a to je pøivádí k Freudovi.
When Freud is the dirtiest man you could think of,
Freud je nejšpinavìjší èlovìk, jakého si umíte pøedstavit,
who has put his ideas into your head.
kterı vám do vašich hlav vloil své myšlenky.
But as if you are already brainwashed people that you accepted all that.
Všechno jste to ale pøijali, jako byste mìli vymyté mozky.
How could you accept Freud? If Freud had come to India,
Jak jste mohli pøijmout Freuda? Kdyby Freud pøišel do Indie,
they would have killed him in no time!
okamitì by ho zabili!
What happens is that, somehow or other - I don't know what is the reason,
Stává se, e jaksi - nevím... jakı je dùvod,
I don't know where to place it, but the wisdom is not there.
nevím, kam to zaøadit, ale není tu ádná moudrost.
There is no maturity, there is no wisdom.
Neexistuje ádná zralost, ádná moudrost.
America I can understand because it is only two-three hundred years old.
Rozumím Americe, protoe je stará jen 200-300 let.
But what about the French? They have not been able
Ale co Francie? Nebyli schopni
to mature but they have become extremely frivolous.
dospìt a stali se extrémnì lehkomyslní.
Maturity is finished.
S dospìlostí je konec.
One of the reasons could be that they want that you should be always young.
Jedním z dùvodù mùe bıt, e chtìjí bıt stále mladí.
In India, young people are called as stupid:
V Indii se mladım lidem øíká blázni,
you call it gadha pachisi, means at twenty-five years they are donkeys.
vy jim øíkáte „Gadha Paèisi“, co znamená, e ve 25 letech jsou osli.
They are never regarded as sensible people to be followed.
Nikdy s nimi není zacházeno jako s rozumnımi lidmi,
And gradually by this movement from Catholic church to Freud,
A postupnì se bìhem tohoto pohybu od katolické církve k Freudovi
what has happened that you haven't got your own personality
stalo, e nemáte vlastní osobnost,
to understand what is right and what is wrong.
abyste pochopili, co je správné a co špatné.
Of course, I must say Sahaja Yogis must have done lots of punyas
Samozøejmì musím øíci, e sahada- jogíni museli dìlat hodnì punjas
and must be very courageous people to be born in this country.
a musí to bıt velmi odvání lidé, e se narodili v této zemi.
Otherwise I don't know how you could have taken your birth here.
Jinak nevím, jak jste se tu mohli narodit.
The law is so funny that they said it depends on the mood of the magistrate,
Zákon je tak podivnı. Øíká se, e závisí na náladì úøadù.
As if, you see, the magistrate doesn't know the law.
Jako by úøedníci neznali zákon.
Such a stupid country in modern times I've never known.
V dnešní dobì jsem se nikdy nesetkala s tak hloupou zemí.
Nowhere in the world there's such a stupid law as it is here.
Nikde na svìtì neexistuje takovı hloupı zákon jako tady.
Of course, in America, there is no justice, they do what they like.
V Americe samozøejmì neexistuje spravedlnost, dìlají si, co chtìjí.
But here is so-called modern people.
Ale tady jsou takzvaní moderní lidé.
What is their condition is that they have no sense of law.
Jejich podmínìností je, e nemají smysl pro právo.
If you ask them, "What is the law?" They don't care.
Pokud se jich zeptáte: „Jakı je zákon?“ Je jim to jedno.
It's the mood of the magistrate.
Je to postoj soudce.
Now supposing he has had a big drink in the last night,
Pøedpokládejme, e vèera hodnì pil,
second day he comes with a hangover, so finished.
druhı den pøijde s kocovinou a to je konec.
And then he will be very much biased towards the drunkards only.
A pak bude velmi pøedpojatı vùèi opilcùm.
So, here it is becoming such a horrible society
Vzniká tu tak strašná spoleènost,
that Indians would be shocked, beyond doubt, but nothing but prostitution.
e by Indové byli bezpochyby šokováni.
To see and to be seen.
Vidìt a bıt vidìn.
Why?
Proè?
Every woman has to dress up in such a way
Kadá ena se musí oblékat tak,
that she should be attractive, for what? Is she a prostitute?
aby byla atraktivní, k èemu? Je to prostitutka?
All kinds of bathroom cultures developed.
Vyvinuly se všechny moné koupelnové kultury.
For example French bath, you know what it means, all over the world.
Napøíklad „francouzská lázeò“, víte, co to znamená, po celém svìtì.
It's a very dirty habit of laziness, it comes because of drinking.
Je to velmi špinavı zvyk z lenosti, která je dùsledkem konzumace alkoholu.
If you drink too much, next morning you are so lethargic
Pokud pijete pøíliš mnoho, pøíštího rána jste natolik letargiètí,
that you take just a French bath and go away.
e si dáte jen „francouzskou koupel“ (støíknete na sebe jen kolínskou) a jdete.
So, please try to remember as French Sahaja Yogis,
Zkuste si jako francouzští sahadajogíni pamatovat,
that your task is much more difficult than the task of other countries,
e váš úkol je obtínìjší ne úkol jinıch zemí,
because it lacks completely wisdom.
protoe zde není úplná moudrost.
Neither you'll find in your institutions, nor in your government,
Nenajdete ji ve svıch institucích, ve vaší vládì
nor in any education.
ani v ádném vzdìlání.
It's lacking wisdom completely.
Moudrost zcela chybí.
And to have wisdom, according to these Freudian people,
Moudrost podle tìch vyznavaèù Freuda
is that you are egoistical!
znamená bıt sobeckı!
They have such funny ideas from the yarn of Mr. Freud
Mají  z repertoáru pana Freuda tak smìšné nápady
that no sensible man would accept.
a ty by ádnı rozumnı èlovìk nepøijal.
But people have lost their senses, and like blotting paper,
Lidé však ztratili zdravı rozum a jako savı papír
whatever is filthy, destructive, horrible, subhuman, they try to absorb.
se snaí absorbovat to, co je špinavé, destruktivní, hrozné, nelidské.
Supposed to be Christian nation.
Údajnì jste køesanskım národem.
Please, all Sahaja Yogis must understand:
Prosím, všichni sahadajogíni to musí pochopit
you must get hold of books and find out, where are we?
- musíte si sehnat knihy a zjistit: „Kde jsme?“
I worked very hard in France, you know that very well.
Ve Francii jsem pracovala velmi tvrdì, víte to moc dobøe.
I used to think, this is the gate of hell.
Myslela jsem, e je to brána do pekla.
But it is much worse than that,
Ale je to mnohem horší ne tohle.
it's a mire of filth. And you are born here
Je to nepoøádek špíny a vy jste se zde narodili
and you have become like lotuses, so fragrant and beautiful,
a stali se jako lotosy, tak voòaví a krásní.
you'll have to fight it out.
Budete s tím muset bojovat.
I am always with you, all My powers with you.
Vdy jsem s vámi, veškerá Moje síla je s vámi.
But remember that you have to fight the society,
Ale pamatujte, e musíte bojovat proti spoleènosti,
you have to save so many people, you have to rescue them.
musíte zachránit tolik lidí, musíte je zachránit.
Children are given liberty, "Do what you like."
Dìti dostávají svobodu: „Dìlejte si, co chcete.“
They have no sense of liberty!
Necítí se svobodnì?
Supposing there's an aeroplane,
Pøedpokládejme, e existuje letadlo,
which was not fixed properly and made to fly.
které nebylo øádnì opraveno, aby mohlo vzlétnout.
What will happen to the aeroplane?
Co se s letadlem stane?
If the children are given liberty without the right sense of their duty
Pokud se dìtem dostane svobody bez náleitého smyslu pro povinnost
and the right sense about themselves, what will happen to them?
a øádného sebe pochopení, co se s nimi stane?
Why children are born to parents? It is to get spoiled,
Proè se dìti rodí rodièùm? Aby byly rozmazlené
to have liberty or to get some guidance?
a mìly svobodu nebo aby dostaly nìjaké vedení?
You cannot guide your children.
Neumíte svoje dìti usmìròovat.
They are so rude, they are so arrogant.
Jsou tak hrubé, tak arogantní.
They have gone off, completely.
Úplnì zpustly.
You know for one month we had to struggle with these western children.
Víte, museli jsme se s tìmi západními dìtmi vypoøádávat mìsíc
And we had come to the point of urge of closing down that school
a byli jsme blízko tomu, abychom tu školu nezavøeli,
because they were really violent children,
protoe to byly skuteènì agresivní dìti,
as if coming from some jungle.
jako by pocházely z dungle.
Even the jungle animals have some sense.
I zvíøata v dungli mají urèitı rozum.
So you have to think about your children.
Musíte myslet na své dìti.
What's going to happen to your children?
Co se stane s vašimi dìtmi?
What is going to be their situation?
Jaká bude jejich situace?
If they are going to live in the same manner in this dirt,
Pokud budou v této špínì ít podle stejnıch pravidel,
these children will turn out to be waste, just a waste!
stane se z nich odpad, jen odpad.
They will have no education, no character, no personality,
Nebudou mít vzdìlání, charakter ani osobnost,
they'll end up with AIDS or with drugs or something like that.
skonèí s AIDS nebo drogami nebo s èímkoli jinım.
I do not see any future for the children of France, no future.
Nevidím pro dìti Francie ádnou budoucnost, ádnou budoucnost.
And you have to fight that, "We want to have future for our children,
Musíte bojovat s heslem: „Chceme budoucnost pro naše dìti,
we don't want them to be ruined."
nechceme, aby byly znièeny.“
And you must have courage to fight it.
Musíte mít odvahu za to bojovat.
It's very important to have courage.
Je velmi dùleité mít odvahu.
If you do not have the courage, you cannot fight it.
Pokud nemáte odvahu, nemùete s tím bojovat.
And today's puja is to give that courage in your hearts.
A dnešní púda má dát tuto odvahu do vašich srdcí.
See it all around you, what's happening?
Podívejte se kolem sebe, co se dìje?
You are all nicely enjoying yourself in the realm of God,
Všichni se máte v Boím království skvìle,
you have entered into the Kingdom of God.
vstoupili jste do Boího království.
But what about the rest of the people?
Ale co zbytek lidí?
The majority of the people, where are they going?
Vìtšina lidí, kam pùjdou?
What is going to be the future of this horrible Mooladhara place?
Jaká bude budoucnost tohoto místa hrozné Muládháry?
Now Freud has been discovered as a fraudulent man,
Teï byl Freud odhalen jako podvodník
and now there are books after so many years,
a po tolika letech jsou (o tom) knihy,
when he has already ruined the people all over the world.
kdy u znièil lidi po celém svìtì.
But the worst of all, they have ruined here.
Ale nejvíce ze všeho bylo znièeno zde.
It's a responsibility specially of the women I think,
Myslím, e je to zodpovìdnost zejména en,
because they are responsible for the society.
protoe jsou odpovìdné za spoleènost.
The society of France has gone to dogs
Francouzská spoleènost šla vniveè
and for you to now take up upon yourself
a vy teï musíte pøevzít odpovìdnost za to,
to talk against this kind of anarchy
e vystoupíte proti takové anarchii,
that is working out the destruction of your families.
která nièí vaše rodiny.
If the women decide, I am sure, they can very, very easily work it out.
Pokud se eny rozhodnou, jsem si jistá, e to velmi snadno zvládnou.
Instead of asking for liberation nonsensical,
Místo toho, abyste ádaly nesmyslnì o osvobození,
you better ask for the ascent of this country.
mìly byste radìji poádat o vzestup této zemì.
I know, I've worked very hard and you are all there.
Vím, e jsem pracovala velmi tvrdì a jste tam všichni.
I am very happy to see that you all are there
Jsem velmi šastná, e vidím, e jste tam všichni,
Because now you should know in a very big way,
Teï byste mìli skuteènì vìdìt,
masses of masses of people will be destroyed.
e široké masy lidí budou znièeny.
Not from without but from within.
Ne zvenèí, ale zevnitø.
Suddenly you'll hear so many millions disappear with this disease.
Najednou uslyšíte, e na tuto nemoc umírá tolik milionù.
Also you must protect yourself, all of you:
Musíte se také chránit, všichni.
always give yourself a bandhan; always lead a clean life.
Vdycky dìlejte bandhan, vdy veïte èistı ivot.
There are certain hygienic rules of Sahaja Yoga, please try to follow them.
V Sahada józe existují urèitá pravidla hygieny,
Do not neglect it.
Nezanedbávejte je.
If somebody gets AIDS, you'll not have him in Sahaja Yoga,
Pokud má nìkdo AIDS, nenechávejte ho v Sahada józe
whatever may be the conditions, whatever may be the reason.
bez ohledu na jeho stav, bez ohledu na dùvod.
You have to be very careful, also I would say never treat a AIDS patient.
Musíte bıt velmi opatrní. Øíkám vám, nikdy neléète pacienta s AIDS.
Like the one yesterday who was arguing with Me,
Jako ten vèera, co se se Mnou hádal.
actually because they have only two types of people:
Ve skuteènosti je to proto, e jsou mezi nimi dva druhy lidí:
one who are arrogant and another one which always
jedni jsou arogantní a druzí si
think that it's better they should die. They have no will to live.
myslí, e by mìli radìji zemøít. Nechtìjí ít.
So there are only two types of people, either right-sided or left-sided.
Existují tedy pouze dva druhy lidí, buï pravostranní, nebo levostranní.
And they can never ascend. We have tried, we have tried.
A nikdy nemohou rùst. Snaili jsme se,
Of course, one person is living for the last seven years,
samozøejmì - jeden z prvních il posledních sedm let,
but still he has no faith in himself.
ale stále v sebe nevìøí.
Maybe next generation might be better on, if they come back.
Moná by pøíští generace mohla bıt lepší, kdyby se vrátila.
But as far as this generation is concerned,
Ale pokud jde o tuto generaci,
you should know your responsibility is very great.
mìli byste vìdìt, e vaše odpovìdnost je velmi velká.
All the Sahaja Yogis must take a vow
Všichni sahadajogíni musí pøísahat,
that they'll fight this society and try to save their country
e budou bojovat proti této spoleènosti
and their countrymen from a complete disaster.
a své krajany pøed úplnou katastrofou.
There is going to be no war,
Válka nebude,
only they will fight themselves and die.
jen budou bojovat mezi sebou a umírat.
It's a very serious matter.
Je to velmi váná vìc.
For that, we decided to have this puja of Durga today
Proto jsme se dnes rozhodli udìlat púdu k Durze,
that all negativity should be destroyed.
protoe veškerá negativita by mìla bıt znièena.
So many Deities build up the body of Kali.
Tolik Bostev tvoøí tìlo Kálí.
Every part of Her body was created by a Deity, looked after by a Deity,
Kadá èást Jejího tìla byla stvoøena Bostvem, chránìna Bostvem,
and is also, later on, is reflected in you all.
a pozdìji se také projeví ve vás všech.
So they say that God has made human beings in His own image,
Øíkají, e Bùh stvoøil èlovìka ke svému obrazu,
I would say, I've made you in My own image,
øekla bych, e jsem vás stvoøila ke svému vlastnímu obrazu,
all the Deities at your disposal.
všechna Bostva máte k dispozici.
They're all with you, and they have created you - if you see it minutely -
Všechna jsou s vámi a stvoøila vás - pokud se na to podíváte podrobnì -
it is the Deities who have brought forth all the beauty that you had.
jsou to Bostva, která pøivedla na svìt
They have made all this beautiful congregation, beautiful transformation,
Udìlala to všechno, krásnou komunitu, krásnou transformaci
and they have created such angelic people out of you.
a udìlala z vás takové andìlské bytosti.
They are always working it out,
Vdy to vyøeší,
but one thing you have to do is to have the drive.
ale jedna vìc, kterou musíte udìlat, je mít vnitøní podnìt.
You had pure desire to ascend, but for what?
Mìli jste èistou touhu rùst, ale na co?
You want to have the light, but for what?
Chcete svìtlo, ale proè?
You want to become gurus, for what?
Chcete se stát guruem, ale na co?
To save people, for their salvation.
Zachránit lidi pro jejich spásu.
Only through your channels I can work out Sahaja Yoga.
Pouze prostøednictvím vašich kanálù mohu pokraèovat v Sahada józe.
If I could work out Myself, I would have.
Kdybych si mohla uvìdomit sama sebe, udìlala bych to.
It's not question of killing one rakshasa.
Nejde o zabití jednoho rákšasa.
God knows how many there are, rakshasas and rakshasas.
Jen Bùh ví, kolik jich je, rákšasù a rákšasù.
And they are everywhere, even within you they were.
A jsou všude, byli dokonce i ve vašem nitru.
Now they have gone away.
Nyní odešli.
So you have to do full justice to Sahaja Yoga, that's very important.
Take musíte plnì ocenit Sahada jógu, to je velmi dùleité.
I knew the puja would be very late, because Kali's puja
Vìdìla jsem, e tato púda bude velmi pozdì, protoe Kálí púda
is always done in the night, after twelve. So it had to be this way.
se dìlá vdy v noci po dvanácté. Take taková musí bıt.
Though last night I slept at four o'clock and I,  tonight,
I kdy jsem vèera v noci usnula ve ètyøi hodiny, dnes veèer
I don't know what time I will sleep - it all works out. It's all worked out.
nevím, jak to dopadne - všechno se vyøeší samo. Všechno je vypracováno.
But you have to have deliberations and you have to think,
Musíte však zváit a pøemıšlet:
“What can we do to change this?”
„Co mùeme udìlat, abychom to zmìnili?“
Why not write some books, why not write some experiences?
Proè nenapsat nìkolik knih, proè nevylíèit pár záitkù?
Get them published in French only. Let the French know what’s happening outside.
Publikujte je pouze ve francouzštinì.
Get some of the books translated –
Pøeloit nìkolik knih
some American books, some English books. At least give quotations from there.
- nìkteré americké knihy, nìkteré anglické knihy.
How they are unaware. First this Catholic church has to go away.
Jak jsou nevìdomí. Nejprve musí odejít katolická církev.
It will, no doubt, I am sure about it. They are literally frightened of us.
Bezpochyby odejde, jsem si tím jista. Doslova se nás bojí.
And we have to now really show them what we are capable of.
A teï jim musíme opravdu ukázat, èeho jsme schopni.
And the funniest thing is that a president has chosen
Nejzábavnìjší je, e si prezident vybral
his lady-friend as the prime minister.
svoji milenku jako pøedsedkyni vlády.
I mean, it’s not possible in any sensible country. It’s never heard of.
Myslím, e to v ádné rozumné zemi není moné.
I must say, English are thousand times better.
Musím øíci, e Anglièané jsou tisíckrát lepší.
They are really very good.
Jsou opravdu velmi dobøí.
At least, as far as administration is concerned,
Alespoò pokud jde o správu,
as far as their parliament is concerned. Their justice is not stupid like this,
o parlament, jejich justice není tak hloupá jako tady,
it’s based on law, not based on the mood of a magistrate.
je zaloena na zákonech a ne na postoji soudce.
How you are still continuing with such stupidity
Jak se stále mùete dret takové hlouposti,
which are really even before medieval age:
která je opravdu pøed støedovìkem
primitive, people are absolutely primitive to accept such laws.
- primitivní, lidé jsou naprosto primi- tivní, e takové zákony pøijímali.
At least you can write a book about the strange laws of French, one title.
Mùete alespoò napsat knihu
How it has harmed. There is a very nice book, “Fraudulent Freud”.
„Jak uškodili.“ Existuje velmi dobrá kniha: „Podvodnı Freud.“
Please read that, and see how Freud has ruined the French,
Pøeètìte si to a podívejte se, jak Freud znièil Francouze,
how their brains are twisted, how they have twisted ideas.
jak pokøivené jsou jejich mozky, jak znetvoøené je jejich myšlení.
You are all so intelligent, clever people.
Vy všichni jste tak inteligentní a moudøí lidé.
So if not with the sword, Kali has to work through the pen.
Kdy ne meèem, musí Kálí pracovat perem.
I never knew it was in that bad shape, though I knew it was.
Vìdìla jsem, e to není dobré,
So this is a challenge for all of us,
Je to tedy vızva pro nás všechny
and let Me see what you can write, all of you, put together your experiences:
a dovolte Mi, abych se podívala, co mùete všichni napsat.
how the French parents behave, how the grandparents behave,
Jak se chovají francouzští rodièe, jak se chovají prarodièe,
what’s happening in this country and all that.
co se dìje v této zemi a podobnì.
They are living in fool’s paradise.
ijí v bláznivém ráji.
They don’t know how destruction is just hanging over their heads.
Nevìdí, e hrozba zkázy jim u visí nad hlavou.
Though you are all saved, but you have to think of others,
I kdy vy všichni jste spaseni, musíte myslet na ostatní.
that is what Sahaja Yoga is, that is not only that we care for the bhaktas –
V Sahada józe nejde u jen o to, e se staráme o bhakty
like Kali just wanted to protect the bhaktas, the sadhakas.
- protoe Kálí chtìla chránit pouze bhakty, sádhaky -
But you have to protect many, many more people.
ale vy musíte ochránit mnohem více lidí.
You have all the powers, just assume them and use them.
Máte všechny pravomoci, prostì si je pøevezmìte a pouijte je.
You can do it.
Jste schopni to udìlat.
Your media is the worst of all
Vaše média jsou ze všech nejhorší.
and we can start a newspaper also calling it anti-media.
Mùeme zaèít vydávat noviny s názvem Anti - media.
What can they do to us?
Co nám mohou udìlat?
Or some sort of an independent name, we can give it.
Nebo jim dáte nìjaké nezávislé jméno.
And it should be open for people who are suffering
Mìly by bıt otevøeny lidem,
from media sensationalization. They can write:
kterım vadí senzacechtivá média. Mohou napsat,
how the media is harming them, how they are giving false reports and things.
jak jim média ubliují, jak podávají nepravdivé zprávy a informace.
We can! Why not?
Umíme to! Proè ne?
I am sure it will work out.
Jsem si jistá, e to bude fungovat.
Think it over what you can do with your pen.
Pøemıšlejte o tom, co mùete s perem dìlat.
Whatever you have gained, whatever you are enjoying: beautiful music,
O tom, co jste získali, co vás tìší: nádherná hudba,
all the pujas, everything. But think of others.
všechny ty púde, všechno ostatní. Ale myslete na ostatní.
They are already drunk and tossing their heads on their pillows.
U jsou opilí a bijí hlavou o polštáøe.
Think of them. They, when will they feel this joy?
Pøemıšlejte o nich. Kdy oni pocítí tuto radost?
I simply feel pity for them
Je Mi jich prostì líto,
that they should have taken to all these bad things,
e kvùli útlaku katolickou církví
because of the suppression of the Catholic church.
pøijali všechny tyto špatné vìci. Byla to katolická církev,
In Sahaja Yoga, we do not do all these things, we are in the centre.
V Sahada józe všechny tyto vìci nedìláme, jsme ve støedu.
We do not have this kind of problems, because we don’t suppress anyone,
Nemáme takové problémy, protoe nikoho nepotlaèujeme,
nor do we go to the other extreme of indulgences.
ani nepùjdeme do druhého extrému shovívavosti.
I think the whole Europe can be divided into two types of people:
Myslím, e celou Evropu lze rozdìlit na dva druhy lidí,
one are Anglo-Saxons, and others are Latins.
jeden je anglosaskı a druhı je latinskı.
Anglo-Saxons are right-sided and the Latins are left-sided:
Anglosasové jsou pravostranní a lidé latinského pùvodu jsou levostranní.
they cry, weep, miserable, they indulge into dirt and filth.
Pláèou, truchlí, jsou nešastní, zabıvají se jen špínou.
Just these two types they are.
Existují pouze tyto dva typy.
Now, unluckily you are in the Latin side.
Bohuel, jste na latinské stranì.
So here, Catholic church is prospering.
Tady se daøí katolické církvi.
Now, if you see to the Latin side and understand
Kdy se podíváte na latinskou stranu, pochopíte,
to what extent they have gone to the left side,
do jaké míry šli na levou stranu
and getting to the left side what diseases you get, very nicely,
a èím onemocníte, kdy se dostanete na levou stranu.
make a list of them.
Peèlivì vytvoøte seznam tìchto nemocí.
So what I said will work out in France:
To, co jsem øekla, by se mìlo ve Francii vyøešit,
the left-sided incurable diseases.
levostranné nevyléèitelné nemoci.
As it is, you walk on the street, you find at least three, four
Skuteènì, kdy se procházíte po ulici, potkáte nejménì tøi, ètyøi
mad people, lunatic people walking, you’ll find them.
šílené lidi, kteøí se chovají jako šílenci. Urèitì je potkáte.
Very simple it is. You don’t have to go to the lunatic asylum, on the street!
Je to jednoduché.
They’ll be all talking and saying things, but it’s all there.
Všichni chtìjí mluvit a nìco vyjádøit. Ale to je vše.
“That’s why they drink, that’s why they are miserable.”.
Proè pijí, proè jsou nešastní.
I do not know what are the statistics of the diseases.
Nevím, jaké jsou statistiky tìchto nemocí.
So the problem is extremely grave, very grave.
Problém je nesmírnì závanı, velmi vánı.
And you have to work it out,
A musíte to vyøešit
with the gravity of your Gurupada which you have asked Me the other day –
pomocí pøitalivosti svého guruovství, o které jste mì jednou poádali
you asked for the status of a guru, for ladies as well as for men.
- poádali jste o status gurua, pro eny i pro mue.
And I said, “All right, start!”
A já jsem øekla: „Dobøe, zaènìte!“
I hope you all have heard the song I’ve made, for asking.
Doufám, e kadı slyšel píseò, kterou jsem napsala na poádání.
[Shri Mataji speaks aside in Marathi]
[maráthí]
All right, once they will sing that song.
Dobøe, tuto píseò jednou zazpívají.
All right.
[maráthí] Dobøe.
They will sing that song to you. There are different requests from the Mother,
Zazpívají vám tuto píseò. Existují rùzné poadavky na Matku,
and in this the last one is that: “Mother, now you give us
vèetnì té poslední: „Matko, dej nám nyní
the Gurupada, the status of a guru.”
gurupadu, status gurua.“
But every guru has a duty: to cleanse the society in which he lives.
Ale kadı guru má povinnost oèistit spoleènost, ve které ije.
It’s his duty, he has to fight it.
Je to jeho povinnost, musí s tím bojovat.
Christ fought it alone, so many saints fought it alone,
Kristus s tím bojoval sám, tolik svatıch bojovalo samotnıch,
they were treated very badly, put in jail, given poisons, things, but they fought it.
bylo s nimi zacházeno velmi špatnì
In the same way you stand on Truth, and you have to fight it.
Vy se stejnım zpùsobem drte pravdy a bojujte za ni.
Because you are saints.
Protoe jste svatí!
May God bless you.
Bùh vám ehnej!